A Finding Aid to the Jackson Pollock and Lee Krasner Papers, circa 1914-1984, bulk 1942-1984, in the Archives of American Art AAA.polljack
Archives of American Art
- Lee Krasner Papers, circa 1927-1984; Series 2; (Box 7-15, 17; 8.6 linear feet)
  - Writings by Others, circa 1965-1981; 2.4
    - B. H. Friedman, "Lee Krasner,", 1965 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Eleanor Munro, untitled manuscript, circa 1977 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Deborah Daw, "Lee Krasner: On Climbing a Mountain of Porcelain", 1979 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - John Myers, "An Imaginary Interview with Lee Krasner", 1981 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Writings by Lee Krasner, circa 1977-1979; 2.5
    This subseries includes a few lecture notes by Lee Krasner as well as handwritten notes about her life and memories.
    - Personal Notes and Lectures, 1977-1979, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Business and Financial Records, circa 1957-1983; 2.6
    Scattered business and financial records date primarily from 1967 to 1983 and include exhibition checklists, conservation forms, loan forms, sales and price lists, warehouse and shipping receipts, guest lists, account statements and other handwritten lists and notes. There is documentation from the Robert Miller Gallery, Pace Gallery, the Whitney museum, and the Marlborough gallery.
    - Miscellaneous Business Records, 1957-1983, undated; (9 folders) (Box 10, Folder 12-20)
    - Sales and Accounting Statements for Robert Miller Gallery, 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Loan Forms and Checklists from "Lee Krasner Retrospective", 1983; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 22-23)
    - Financial Records, 1967-1977 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Inventories, Marlborough Gallery, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Inventories, Pace Gallery, 1975-1981 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Inventories, Robert Miller Gallery, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Price Lists, 1972, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Mailing Lists, Marlborough Gallery, 1968, 1973; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 29-30)
    - Mailing Lists, Whitney Museum, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Mailing Lists, Pace Gallery, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Mailing Lists, Whitney Museum, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Mailing Lists, Pace Gallery, 1979, 1981; (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 34-35)
    - Mailing Lists, Robert Miller Gallery, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Guest Lists, Robert Miller Gallery, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Scrapbook, 1965; 2.7
    This scrapbook documents a 1965 exhibition of Krasner's work at Whitechapel Gallery in London. The scrapbook was created by the President of Marlborough Gallery, Pierre Levai, and includes news clippings about the event and photographs of the exhibition installation.
    - Whitechapel Gallery Exhibition Scrapbook, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Printed Material, circa 1942-1984; 2.8
    Printed material documents Lee Krasner's career and includes solo and group exhibition catalogs, announcements, press releases, and numerous newspaper and magazine clippings. There are also newsletters, event calendars, annual reports, and documentary film announcements for films about Krasner. Schedules, directories, instructions, and other faculty materials are from Krasner's semester as a faculty member at Cooper Union. Miscellaneous printed material includes primarily programs, brochures, and invitations to events. There is also an "Odds and Ends" folder. Items are arranged by type of material and chronologically within each folder.
    - Exhibition Catalogs, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1942-1963; (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 40-42)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1964-1975; (7 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-7)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1976-1981; (10 folders) (Box 11, Folder 8-17)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1982-1984; (4 folders) (Box 12, Folder 1-4)
    - Exhibition Announcements, 1949-1984, undated; (4 folders) (Box 12, Folder 5-8)
    - Press Releases, 1958-1983, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1968-1983, undated; (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
    - Documentary Film Announcements, 1972-1983 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Essay, "Jackson Pollock Works on Paper", undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Reproductions of Artwork, circa 1981-1982, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Essay, "The American Abstract Expressionist Collection of the Sarah Campbell Blaffer Foundation", undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Newsletters, Events Calendars, and Annual Reports, 1960-1984, undated; (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 16-17)
    - Selected Chronology, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Exhibition info for "Lee Krasner at Martha Jackson", 1958 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Faculty Materials, The Cooper Union, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - The Subject of the Artist, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Exhibition Materials for "Krasner/Pollock: A Working Relationship", 1981 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - 25 Artists, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - "Odds & Ends", 1969-1970, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - New Clippings, undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - News Clippings, 1948-1974; (5 folders) (Box 12, Folder 26-30)
    - News Clippings, 1975-1979; (4 folders) (Box 12, Folder 31-34)
    - News Clippings, 1981-1984; (6 folders) (Box 13, Folder 1-6)
    - Magazine Clippings, 1952-1984, undated; (3 folders) (Box 13, Folder 7-9)
    - Photographs of Artists in Harper's Bazaar (Reproductions), 1951; (Not scanned) (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Exhibition Poster, 1969; (Not scanned) (Box 17 (sol), Folder 1)
  - Photographs, circa 1929-1983; 2.9
    Lee Krasner's personal photographs and photographs of her artwork are filed here, including one of her painting in the studio and portraits of her at the WPA pier. The majority of the photographs in this subseries are professional portraits taken of Lee Krasner throughout her career. Some of the portraits depict her home and painting in her studio. Photographers of note are Hans Namuth, Renate Ponsold, and Ray Eames, and one by Irving Penn. All portraits of Krasner are grouped by photographer and arranged chronologically.
    Personal and family photographs include photos of Krasner on the beach, circa 1939, and with family and friends. Photographs of Krasner with Jackson Pollock were taken at the beach, with family, and at their home in the Springs. There are also photographs of the two of them outside of their home and in the studio, taken by Wilfred Zogbaum. There are photographs of Lee Krasner at various exhibitions, including her 1973 exhibition at the Whitney Museum of American Art.
    Photographs of artwork include photographs of Krasner's work in various medium, such as ink, collage, lithographs, and mosaic, as well as the artwork she did for the WPA. Photographs of artwork have not been scanned.
    - Personal Photographs, 1938-1982, undated; 2.9.1
      - Early Portraits of Lee Krasner, 1938-1940, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Lee Krasner at the WPA Pier, circa 1942 (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Lee Krasner Personal and Family Photographs, circa 1939-1964, undated; (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
      - Lee Krasner and Jackson Pollock, circa 1950, undated; (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 15-16)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Maurice Berezov, circa 1942, 1956, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Hans Namuth, 1955, 1958, undated; (Oversized items in Box 17, F2) (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Halley Erskine, 1959; (Oversized items in Box 17, F3) (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Paul De Vries, circa 1960-1961; (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 20-21)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Hans Namuth, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Ray Eames, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 23)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Bryan Wharton, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Bob Miller, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 25)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Mark Patiky, 1970; (Oversized items in Box 17, F4) (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Portraits of Krasner by John Reed, circa 1970 (Box 13, Folder 27)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Irving Penn, 1972; (Oversized items in Box 17, F5) (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Iris Schneider, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 29)
      - Portraits of Krasner by David Gahr, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 30)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Ann Chwatsky, circa 1975 (Box 13, Folder 31)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Marjorie Michael, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 32)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Ray Eames, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 33)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Lenore Seroka, circa 1977 (Box 13, Folder 34)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Renate Ponsold, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 35)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Jesse Fernandez, circa 1979 (Box 13, Folder 36)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Ernst Hans, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 37)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Waintrob-Budd, 1981; (Oversized items in Box 17, F6) (Box 13, Folder 38)
      - Portraits of Krasner, Miscellaneous, 1950-1982, undated; (2 folders; Oversized items in Box 17, F7) (Box 13, Folder 39-40)
      - Lee Krasner's Home by Ray Eames, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 41)
      - Lee Krasner's Home by Jesse Fernandez, 1973, 1979, undated; (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 42-43)
      - Exhibition, University of Alabama, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 44)
      - Exhibition, Whitney Museum, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 45)
      - Exhibition, Brandeis University, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 46)
      - Exhibition, "Around Jackson Pollock: East Hampton, the 1950s", 1979 (Box 13, Folder 47)
      - Exhibition, Centre Georges Pompidou, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 48)
      - Exhibitions, Miscellaneous, 1974, undated (Box 13, Folder 49)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Hans Namuth, 1955, 1958, undated; (Scanned with Box 13, F18) (Box 17 (sol), Folder 2)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Halley Erskine, 1959; (Scanned with Box 13, F19) (Box 17 (sol), Folder 3)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Mark Patiky, 1970; (Scanned with Box 13, F26) (Box 17 (sol), Folder 4)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Irving Penn, 1972; (Scanned with Box 13, F28) (Box 17 (sol), Folder 5)
      - Portraits of Krasner by Waintrob-Budd, 1981; (Scanned with Box 13, F38) (Box 17 (sol), Folder 6)
      - Portraits of Krasner, Miscellaneous, 1950-1982, undated; (Scanned with Box 13, F39-40) (Box 17 (sol), Folder 7)
    - Photographs of Artwork, 1929-1983, undated; 2.9.2; (not scanned)
      - Charcoal Drawings, 1937-1939 (Box 13, Folder 50)
      - Oil on Paper, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 51)
      - Early Abstractions, 1938-1943 (Box 13, Folder 52)
      - Artwork for the WPA, circa 1940-1942 (Box 13, Folder 53)
      - Little Image Paintings, 1946-1950; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
      - Ink Paintings, 1950-1958 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Paintings, 1942-1965, undated; (8 folders; Oversized items in Box 17, F8) (Box 14, Folder 4-11)
      - Mosaic Table, 1947; (Oversized items in Box 17, F9) (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Studies for Mosaic Project, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Collages, 1953-1979; (3 folders) (Box 14, Folder 14-16)
      - Lithographs, 1962-1963 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - Miscellaneous Artwork by Lee Krasner, 1929-1935, undated; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 18-19)
      - Unidentified Artwork, undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - Stable Gallery Collage Exhibition, 1955; (Oversized items in Box 17, F10) (Box 14, Folder 21)
      - Howard Wise Gallery Exhibition, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - Marlborough Gallery Exhibition, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - Marlborough Gallery Exhibition, 1969; (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 24-25)
      - University of Alabama Exhibtion, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 26)
      - Reese Palley Gallery Exhibition, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 27)
      - Marlborough Gallery Exhibition, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 28)
      - Whitney Museum Exhibition, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 29)
      - Janie C. Lee Gallery Exhibition, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 30)
      - Pace Gallery Exhibition, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 31)
      - Janie C. Lee Gallery Exhibition, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 32)
      - Nassau County Museum of Art Exhibition, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 33)
      - Grey Art Gallery Exhibition, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 34)
      - Guild Hall Exhibition, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 35)
      - Pace Gallery Exhibition, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 36)
      - Tate Gallery Exhibition, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 37)
      - Unidentified Exhibitions, 1954-1959, 1976, undated (Box 14, Folder 38)
      - Drawing by Tony Smith, 1945-1946 (Box 14, Folder 39)
      - Miscellaneous Proof Sheets, undated (Box 14, Folder 40)
      - Negatives, undated (Box 14, Folder 41)
      - Color Transparencies, 1938-1972, undated; (3 folders) (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
      - Paintings, 1942-1962, undated; (See also Box 14, F4-11) (Box 17 (sol), Folder 8)
      - Mosaic Table, 1947; (See also Box 14, F12) (Box 17 (sol), Folder 9)
      - Stable Gallery Collage Exhibition, 1955; (See also Box 14, F21) (Box 17 (sol), Folder 10)
  - Audio and Video Recordings, circa 1964-1983; 2.10
    This subseries consists primarily of audio recordings of interviews with Lee Krasner that discuss her career, her relationship with Jackson Pollock, and Pollock's career. The recordings include interviews conducted by John Gruen for the Casper Citron radio show, one for the Martha Dean radio show, and one for the "Today Show". Another interview of note was conducted by fellow artist Mercedes Matter. Transcripts for most of these interviews are filed in Series 2.3.
    Also found in this series are two recorded lectures given by Lee Krasner, and two copies VHS video recordings about Pollock and a 1982 exhibition of his work, "Pollock a Beaubourg". Items are arranged chronologically.
    - Lee Krasner Lecture at Nassau County Museum of Art, undated; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Bruce Glaser Interview of Lee Krasner, undated; 1 sound tape reels Includes letter from Glaser and notes. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Mercedes Matter Interview of Lee Krasner, undated; 1 sound tape reels Original; 1 Sound discs (CD) Duplicate (Box 15, Folder 6)
      CD is access copy.
    - John Gruen Interview of Lee Krasner, 1964; 2 Sound discs (lacquer) Original; 1 sound tape reels Duplicate; 2 Sound cassettes Duplicates (Box 15, Folder 7-9)
      Cassettes are access copies.
    - Martha Dean Radio Show Interview of Lee Krasner, 1968; 1 Sound cassettes Duplicate; 1 sound tape reels Original (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
      Cassette is access copy.
    - Dolores Holmes Interview of Lee Krasner, 1971; 1 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - NBC "Today Show" Interview of Lee Krasner, 1973; 1 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Lee Krasner Appearance on the 6PM News, 1973 November; 1 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Sarah Faunce Interview of Lee Krasner, 1977; 1 sound tape reels (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - University Lectures by Lee Krasner, 1977; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - WQXR Radio Interview of Lee Krasner, 1980; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified Interview with Lee Krasner, undated; 1 Sound cassettes Poor sound quality at first; improves around 36 min. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified radio interview with Lee Krasner, Robert Indiana, and Paul Jenkins, 1976; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - "Pollock a Beaubourg", 1982-1983; 1 Videocassettes (U-matic); 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 15, Folder 18-19)
    - John Gruen Interview of Lee Krasner, 1964; 2 Sound discs (lacquer); (See also Box 15, F9) (Box 17 (sol))